

Hatem Lamine

Full-stack web developer

Application context:

I am a full-stack web developer with over 3 years of experience, based in Tunis, Tunisia. Currently, I'm a 5th-year software engineering student at INSAT, and I'm planning a mandatory six-month end-of-study internship starting anytime after I'll have completed my studies on 13/01/2024. (PS: This is how I managed studying while working full-time in the past.)

| My portfolio | • |
|--------------|---|
|--------------|---|

My web-apps

hatemlaminee@gmail.com

+216 93 684 137

linkedin.com/in/hatem-lamine in

github.com/Hatem902

EXPERIENCE

Full-stack Web Developer 12/2021 - 11/2023 (2 years)

XQuant - Seoul, South Korea · Full-time · Remote

- Proposed and implemented an infinite scrolling solution resulting in an exceptional user experience and a 10x performance increase. (Through transforming an initial 6 seconds loading time into virtually unnoticeable 50ms loading times as the user scrolls down.)
- Participated in PR reviews to maintain quality standards.
 - Made decisions paired with constructive comments and feedback, to approve or reject merges involving multiple features, fixes, and refactors.
- Wrote end-to-end high-quality code for complex features.
 - Such as comparing two documents side by side (like github commits), managing user workspaces, and exposing analytical statistics for contract documents.

Tech: Next.js · React · Node.js · TypeScript · Tailwind · Radix UI · React Query + Axios · React Hook Forms · Zod · Docker

Full-stack Web Developer

11/2020 - 10/2021 (1 year)

EY - Tunis, Tunisia · Full-time · On-site

- Set-up advanced API endpoints with optimized DB queries, and schema validation.
 - Created customizable frontend pages and components that consume them while maintaining end-to-end type safety, graceful error handling, and efficient caching. (In collaboration with the UX/UI design team.)
 - Designed optimal data structures for complex features.
- Set up **End-to-End Tests** using Cypress with a Test-Driven Development (TDD) approach.
- Contributed to the architectural decisions for two modules within GTES (EY's Global Tax E-invoicing Solution), ensuring a precise alignment with the business requirements.

Tech: Next.js · React · Node.js · TS · Tailwind · React Query · React Hook Forms \cdot Zod \cdot Docker \cdot Cypress

Full-stack Web Developer 04/2020 - 09/2020 (6 months)

Keyrus - Tunis, Tunisia · Internship · On-site

Migrated a large expense management solution from Nuxt.js 2 to Nuxt.js 3 and created end-to-end features.

Tech: Vue 3 · Nuxt 3 · TS · Node.js · Express.js

Front-end Web Developer 01/2020 - 02/2020 (2 months)

UpKurs - Tunis, Tunisia · Internship · On-site

Implemented 20% of the front-end material for a videoconferencing app, in collaboration with the UX/UI team.

Tech: Angular · TS · CSS · Node.js · Nest.js · Figma

TECH STACK

- Full-stack: Next.js, React, Node.js, TypeScript, React Query + Axios, Zustand/Jotai, Tailwind CSS, Radix UI, Shadon UI, React Portals, MySQL, Redis, PostgreSQL, PlanetScale, UpStash, Drizzle ORM, Prisma, NextAuth, Clerk, Stripe, React Hook Forms, Zod, Express.js, tRPC, Cypress.
- DevOps: Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, AWS, Azure, Vercel.
- Basics: JS, TS, CSS, HTML, Git.
- **Concepts:** Performance Optimization, Queries & Caching, Error Handling, E2E Testing, Software Architecture, UX/UI Design, SEO.

EDUCATION

INSAT University - Tunis · 2019 - Present (5th year).

Software engineering

Expected software engineering degree in 2024.

Pioneer High School Of Nabeul · 2015 – 2019

Baccalaureate mathematics

Grade: 17.41/20, honors. Rank: 642

PROJECTS

Best in Role (peaked 50k+ users)

Esports Voting Platform & Leaderboard, created for the 2023 League of Legends World Championship event.

Demo ⊘ Website ♥ Source ■ My Design 1 Web Vitals

Targeted application requirements:

- 1- Performance Immediate reactivity through:
 - o optimistic updates, lazy loading, efficient caching, parallel queries. Lighthouse Performance score: 100.
- 2- Intuitive, clean UX/UI design: color shades, whitespace, visual hierarchy, responsiveness, attention allocation.
- 3- SEO: Metadata, favicons, sitemaps, OpenGraph images.
 - o advertised it through self-promotion & reaching out to influencers on X (Twitter), Reddit, and Twitch.
 - o Lighthouse SEO score: 100.
- 4- Maintainability: Type safety end-to-end, schema validation, customizable typesafe reusable components.

Tech: Next.js App Router & Route handlers · React · Node · TS React Query · Tailwind · ShadcnUI · MySQL · PlanetScale · Zod

E-Commerce + Dashboard & CMS (Demo / Website / Source)

- · Admin Dashboard exposing statistics such as total revenue, sales, and products in stock + a highly customizable CMS.
- Multi-platform image upload, auth, stores with seamless navigation & filtering, and cart management & payment.

Tech: Next.js 13.4 · React · Node · TS · React Query · Tailwind · Shadcn UI · Zod · React Hook Form · Stripe · MySQL · PlanetScale.

Text Similarity API (Demo / Website / Source)

· Measures text similarity using OpenAI's utilities, and a comprehensive API key system with rate limitation.

Tech: Next.js 13.2 · React · Node · TS · Tailwind · Radix UI · PlanetScale · Prisma · Upstash · NextAuth.

Spotify 2 (Demo /Showcase /Website /Source /My Design)

• A redesigned Spotify experience via your real Spotify account.

Tech: Next.js · React · Spotify API · NextAuth · OAuth & JWT

LANGUAGES

- Enalish
- French

Arabic

HOBBIES

Piano, music theory, design, hiking, journaling, working out.